# Gijs Wels



20.00

05/29/1997



+31611856348



gijswels@gmail.com



Amsterdam



gijswels.github.io

# Qualities

- People oriented
- ◆ Curious
- ◆ Independent
- ◆ Team player
- Solution oriented

# Languages



# **Industrial Design Engineer**

I am an industrial designer with a focus on physical products and the relationships we create between people and their world through design - the new behaviours and experiences they enable. I have a special interest in well-being, innovation, and good design, both aesthetically and practically. I learned that it is not only important to dream but also to realise. This results in a hardworking person who motivates those around him to achieve the same goals - to make things happen!

# Education

# MSc Integrated Product Design

May 29, 2024

TU Delft, Delft

» Product(-service) design, concept design, technical prototyping, and manufacturing. Thesis - Empowering Psychosocial Well-Being at the Workplace.

# BSc Industrial Design Engineering

2021

TU Delft, Delft

» Technology, bussiness, people, and design.

# Minor Architecture

Grade - 9

2019

2015

TU Delft, Delft

» House of the future, analysing global trends, and spatial design and planning.

VWO+

s.g. Spieringshoek, Schiedam

# Extracurricular

#### Ambassadeurs van Amsterdam

09/2024 - 12/2024

De Bildung Academie, Amsterdam

Tackling a societal issue, developing a project plan in a diverse group, and running a pilot.

#### Summer School

07/2023 - 08/2023

Aalto University, Helsinki

» Design environments in balance with nature in an international and multidisciplinary group.

#### Exchange

01/2023 - 06/2023

Chalmers University, Gothenburg

» UX, form & manufacturing, manufacturing strategy, and introduction in data science & AI.

#### Internship

09/2020 - 02/2021

DigiNova, Delft

 $\,{}_{^{>\!\!\!\!>}}$  UX/UI, human-system interaction, and development. Applications for robots in healthcare.

# **Employment**

#### Royal Ahrend

10/2023 - 05/2024

Office Furniture, Sint-Oedenrode

» Graduation project. Studying behaviour, work culture, and employee well-being (stress).

#### MBO Riinland

02/2019 - 06/2019

Secretary School, Gouda

» Teaching assistent.

### Frankeland

08/2012 - 02/2023

Nursing Home, Schiedam

» Host. Bridge between elderly and management.

# **Noteworthy Achievements**

# Micro-Break Communication Tool

Royal Ahrend, Sint-Oedenrode

By creating social awareness the goal is to counter the rising trend of burnout complaints.

2024

2023

2021

My thesis is selected for Human Factors NL thesis award and I got selected to speak at the Vital Work-event at the High Tech Campus.

### Natural Seating

Aalto University, Helsinki

» Seat to connect with nature; focus on functionality, minimalistic design and biodegradability.

I got selected by my faculty to participate in an international and multidisciplinary project about the use of wood in balance with nature.

### Adjustable School Chair

Royal Ahrend, Sint-Oedenrode

» Desk chair for Dutch primary education; adjustable to all students from the age of 5 to 12.

High difficulty. An ergonomically almost impossible task, but I fondly look back on it. Ahrend wants to release the chair in the future.

#### Adaptable City Square

The Green Village, Delft

» Bachelor thesis; green solution to the urban heat island effect in the municipality of Delft.

Of all thirty participating students, my solution got selected by the organisation to continue.

















# nature's seat



## Skills

#### 3D Modelling

SolidWorks Rhinoceros Drawing

### Visual Communication

Drawing Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Adobe Premiere

# Digital Prototyping

Adobe Dreamweaver Android Studio Figma Axure Adobe XD Arduino & Raspberry

# Physical Prototyping

Rapid Prototyping Workshop Experienced

#### I know my way around

HTML CSS JavaScript Python Mathlab Arduino Raspberry Pi